Oliver Tambo Papers 2000.0144
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series A: Personal Documents, 1960-1993
  - Speeches and Statements
    - Published in the form of pamphlets, journal articles, etc. (Box A17., Folder 2)
      - 1967-1984 (Box A17., Folder 2.1)
        - Speech published in Sechaba, presented at a meeting of the Women's Section, 1981 December
        - Statement at the Second National Conference of Solidarity with the Peoples of Southern Africa, Rome, published in Sechaba, 1982 February 26 - 28
        - Statement - In Combat, ANC Department of Information and Publicity, 1983 April
        - President's message for 1984 - Sechaba, 1984 January
        - Clarion Call to all Opponents of Apartheid, Press Conference with Oliver Tambo held under the auspices of the Greater London Council in County Hall. Booklet Published by the ANC, 1984 March 21
        - Speech published in Sechaba at the Solomon Mahalngu Freedom College, 1984 October
      - 1985-1990 (Box A17., Folder 2.2)
        - "The Ideology of Racism." Miscellaneous article.
        - Render South Africa Ungovernable. Message of the National Executive Committee on the occasion of 8 January 1984, delivered by Oliver Tambo. Issued by the ANC. (Duplicate. See also: National Executive Committee - Statements).
        - "Address to the Nation," Radio Freedom. Issued by the ANC, London, 1985 July 22
        - ANC Press Statement presented by President Oliver Tambo, Lusaka, 1985 August 16
        - "Attack, Advance - Give the Enemy no Quarter," Message of the National Executive Committee on the Occasion of 8th January 1986, Delivered by Oliver Tambo. Issued by the ANC, Lusaka. (Duplicate. See Also: National Executive Committee - Statements).
        - "Support the Sacrifices we are Making," Address to the Royal Commonwealth Society, London, 1986 June 23
        - Racism, Apartheid and a New World Order, Third World Lecture 1986. Third World Foundation/Monograph 15.
        - Statement of the National Executive Committee (NEC) on the occasion of the 75th Anniversary of the ANC. Presented by Oliver Tambo. Published in the form of a pamphlet/brochure: 8 January 1987 - ANC calls for advance to People's Power. (Duplicate. See also: National Executive Committee - Statements), 1987 January 8
        - Booklet published by the ANC on the occasion of the 75th Anniversary of the organisation. (Includes statements by Oliver Tambo)
        - United Action for People's Power. Message to the People of South Africa from the National Executive Committee on the occasion of 8 January 1987. Issued by the ANC. (Duplicate. See also: National Executive Committee - Statements)
        - Olaf Palme Memorial Lecture on Disarmament and Development. Edited by Cora Weiss. Riverside Church, 1987 January 21
        - "Here, No Surrenders." PNP Founder's Day Banquet (see main body of speeches and statements/1987 for transcript of keynote address contained in this publication), 1987 July 4
        - Radio Freedom, Addis Ababa, Text of Programme entitled - "Away with the Rule of Martial Law." (Includes excerpt by Oliver Tambo), 1987 June 11
        - South Africa at the Crossroads, Canon Collins Memorial Lecture. Published by the British Defence and Aid Fund for Southern Africa (1988), 1987 May 28
        - South Africa at the Crossroads: Speeches delivered in May 1987 to Business International, The Canon Collins Memorial Lecture and to the World Council of Churches. Issued by the ANC, Lusaka.
        - Speech delivered at PNP Founder's Day Banquet - July 4, 1987. Miscellaneous publication.
        - "Strategies Options for International Companies," The Black Scholar, 1987 December
        - Forward to Mass Action for People's Power! Statement of the National Executive Committee on the occasion of the 77th Anniversary of the ANC. Presented by Oliver Tambo. (Duplicate. See also: National Executive Committee - Statements), 1989
        - Mass Action for People's Power! (Published on a different format. See also: NEC - Statements)
        - Pamphlet: Message to the re-launch of the ANC Women’s League, Durban, 1990 August 9
    - Struggle for Liberation in South Africa and Responsibility of the United Nations: Addresses, 1963-1982 collected and edited by E. S. Reddy (Box A17., Folder 3)
  - Audio/Visual Material (Box A18)
    - Video Tapes (Box A18., Folder 1)
      - Oliver Tambo (Box A18., Folder 1.1)
        - Footage of Oliver Tambo recuperating after his stroke in Sweden (Box A18., Folder 1.1.1)
        - National Press Club - Guest: Oliver Tambo (Box A18., Folder 1.1.2)
        - Various Interviews - Australia n Television, 1987 (Box A18., Folder 1.1.3)
      - Nelson Mandela: (Box A18., Folder 1.2)
        - Nelson Mandela - Freedom at Seventy. An Indian Tribute: World Youth Action against Apartheid. (Doordarshan Delhi Presentation.)/Prometheus Bound - Nelson Mandela. (Devised and Produced by S. Raghava Chari, Delhi Doordarshan Production) (Box A18., Folder 1.2.1)
        - Nelson Mandela 70th Birthday Tribute ( Elephant House Productions, 1988 June 11 (Box A18., Folder 1.2.2)
        - Nelson Mandela Tribute, Wembley Concert - Part 2 ( IDAF), 1990 (Box A18., Folder 1.2.3)
        - Nelson Mandela's visit to Lusaka (Box A18., Folder 1.2.4)
      - Winnie Mandela (Box A18., Folder 1.3)
        - Footage of funeral tribute: Velani V. Tula [ Winnie Mandela and "Mandela Team" present] (Box A18., Folder 1.3.1)
        - Interview for BBC TV News with Winnie Mandela on the Stompie Mokhetsi affair [Duplicate] (Box A18., Folder 1.3.2)
        - Footage of Winnie Mandela speaking at a graduation ceremony (clergy), Pietersburg, 1988 (Box A18., Folder 1.3.3)
        - Network - SABC - " Winnie Mandela Controversy", 1989 February 23 (Box A18., Folder 1.3.4)
      - Other Individuals (Box A18., Folder 1.4)
        - Kader Asmal: Saturday Live Presented by Kader Asmal, 1988 January 30 (Box A18., Folder 1.4.1)
        - Johnny Makatini, Funeral (Box A18., Folder 1.4.2)
        - E. J. Mabuza (Chief Minister of Kangwane): Interview with E. J. Mabuza on Network ( SABC). Interviewer: Nigel Murphy (Box A18., Folder 1.4.2)
        - Andrew Molotsansy Footage of Andrew Molotsansy in New Zealand (Includes footage of marches opposing a rugby tour by South Africa) (Box A18., Folder 1.4.3)
        - David Webster, Funeral/Tribute (Duplicate) (Box A18., Folder 1.4.4)
      - African National Congress, Women's Section (Box A18., Folder 1.5)
        - Second ANC Women's National Conference, Luanda, Angola (Box A18., Folder 1.5.1)
        - ANC Video Training Project, " SOMAFCO Art Workshops"/"Youth for Liberation", 1987 April (Box A18., Folder 1.5.2)
        - SOMAFCO 10th Anniversary (Box A18., Folder 1.5.3)
        - 75th Anniversary (Box A18., Folder 1.5.4)
          - Tape 58: Public Meeting/Song/ Oliver Tambo's Speech/Songs/K.K. Speech/Minute to remember dead
          - Tape 59: Kaunda continued. Press Conference ( Afravision)
      - Documentaries and other Miscellaneous Items (Box A18., Folder 1.6)
        - 15 Anni Di Solidarieta' Italiana Con I Popoli Dell'Africa Australe (a cura di G Soncini - Reggio Emilia) [Includes footage of Oliver Tambo] (Box A18., Folder 1.6.1)
        - "The Africa Prize for Leadership," Announcement News Conference, Lusaka, Zambia, and UN Headquarters in New York, 1988 July 21 (Box A18., Folder 1.6.2)
        - Changing this Country: The testimony of four South African workers (58 minute documentary produced and edited by Peter Entell for the International Labour Office) (Box A18., Folder 1.6.3)
        - Amakomansi: 1921 - 1986/SACP ( Inkululeko Film Productions) (Box A18., Folder 1.6.4)
        - The Anvil and the Hammer. Director - Barry Feinberg ( IDAF, 1988) (Box A18., Folder 1.6.5)
        - Fight Mabhida Fight. Director: Mario Borgneth (Kanemo Producao e Comunicacao) (Box A18., Folder 1.6.6)
        - The Cry of Reason ( Beyers Naudé ) [Worldwide Documentary] (Includes preview cassette) (Box A18., Folder 1.6.7)
        - In Remembrance of Martin ( Martin Luther King, Jr. Centre for Nonviolent Social Change, Inc.) (Box A18., Folder 1.6.8)
        - ABC News Nightline, Reports from South Africa, 1985 (Box A18., Folder 1.6.9)
        - Zuid Afrika op weg naar morgen ( VARA televisie, 2 hours) [Includes interviews with Oliver Tambo; Beyers Naudé and Alan Boesak), 1986 September 5 (Box A18., Folder 1.6.10)
        - Dispatches (Television Actuality Programme, Channel Four), "Apartheid's Assassins,", 1990 April 5 (Box A18., Folder 1.6.11)
        - BUWA! ( South African United Artists) (Box A18., Folder 1.6.12)
        - Hiroshima and Nagasaki - The Harvest of Nuclear War (English Version) (Box A18., Folder 1.6.13)
        - Documentary of the life of Solomon T. Plaatje/Funeral of Victoria Mxenge (Box A18., Folder 1.6.14)
    - Audio Cassettes (Box A18., Folder 2)
      - Oliver Tambo (Box A18., Folder 2.1)
        - Autobiographical Notes (Box A18., Folder 2.1.1)
          - Cassette No 6 (Tapes 11 and 12): The School/St. John's Kraal (Box A18., Folder 2.1.1.1)
          - Cassette No 8 (Tapes 15 and 16): I fall among thieves and a horse is lost/A castle-in-the-air collapses into (Ex VI)/A 2nd Castle-in-the-air collapses into (Ex VI No.2)/The 3rd stands firm on the ground/at last the Ngele mountain range is conquered (Box A18., Folder 2.1.1.2)
          - Cassette 9 (Tapes 17 and 18) Student at St. Peter's Secondary School, Rosettenville (Box A18., Folder 2.1.1.3)
          - Cassette 10 (Tapes 17 and 20): More on June Holidays, 1934/Black and White - First Impression/A Heart-Rending Telegramme/Bizana revisited, 1935/Mrs. Elaine Melville/Another Heart-rending telegram/Problem of school fees/hopes for Lovedale Scholarship are dashed/St. Peter's J C Exams rock South Africa (Box A18., Folder 2.1.1.4)
          - Cassette 14 (Tapes 26 and 27): Fort Hare Continued (Box A18., Folder 2.1.1.5)
        - Statements/Speeches: (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2)
          - 26 June 1969, Lusaka: (6 items) (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.1)
            - Chairman's Opening Address (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.1.1)
              June 26 Choir - Vukani Mawethu; ZAPU Representative (T.G.)
            - ZAPU Representative (T.G.) continued (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.1.2)
              Frelimo Representative (Koufa); SWAPO Representative
            - SWAPO Representative (continued) (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.1.3)
              MPLA Representative (Alphonso); June 26 Choir - Hambe Kahle; HEPR (Nkolosa)
            - HEPR (Nkolosa) continued (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.1.4)
              Honourable Minister - P Matoka; ANC Acting President - Oliver Tambo
            - ANC Acting President - Oliver Tambo (cont.) (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.1.5)
            - 1. ANC Acting President - Oliver Tambo (cont.) (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.1.6)
              June 26 choir - Give a thought to Africa and Tiyende Pamosi; Chairman’s closing remarks; National Anthem
            - Radio Broadcast (7.10am): Address at June 26 meeting ( Evelyn Hone College of further studies) (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.1.7)
          - MK Graduation Ceremony, Introduction - Oliver Tambo; Presentation - Joe Modise; March Past and Songs, 1977 November 28 (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.2)
          - Speech given by Oliver Tambo at a graduation ceremony of cadres and combatants of Umkhonto we Sizwe, ( Angola?), 1977 November 28 (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.3)
          - Moncada Graduation? (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.4)
            - Side 1: Oliver Tambo on the Closure of the Second Course, 1979 August 6
            - Side 2: Speech to President of the MPLA, preceded by choir
          - New Year Message, 1979 January 8 (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.5)
          - Mazimbu - Dakawa Message: Year of the Cadre (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.6)
          - (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.6a)
            - Side 1: Introduction to a gathering honouring the ANC by the Prime Minister of Madagascar (Includes history of struggle for liberation/Malagas Revolution)
            - Side 2: Introduction continued/ ANC Speaker: Oliver Tambo
          - President Oliver Tambo's speech - AKFM Head Quarters, Tananarive, Madagascar, 1980 March 19 (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.7)
          - Karl Renner Institute Address, Austria (2 cassettes), 1980 November 20 (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.8)
            - a) Speaker - Oliver Tambo
            - b) Questions (poor recording)
          - Speech by President Samora Machel (with Interpreter) and President Oliver Tambo, Mass Rally, Maputo, 1982 February 14 (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.9)
          - Olaf Palme Memorial Lecture on Disarmament and Development, 1987 January 21 (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.10)
            - Tape 1: Sechaba; William Sloane Coffin; Joe Martenson; Cheryl Partham; Dr Allan Boesak; Cora Weiss; Anders Ferm
            - Tape 2: Clamm Dole; William Sloane Coffin; Oliver Tambo; Anthem
          - Oliver Tambo: Call to the People, 1988 May 6 (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.11)
          - The Africa Fund Reception honouring Oliver Tambo at Roosevelt House, NYC (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.12)
          - Message to the SACP Congress, 1989 April (Box A18.2.1.2.13, Folder 2.1.2.13)
          - Oliver Tambo’s address to OAU Summit, (duplicate) [Broadcast: Radio Freedom], 1989 July 25 (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.14)
          - Department of Information and Publicity: Speaker - Oliver Tambo, undated (Box A18., Folder 2.1.2.15)
        - Press Conferences/Interviews (Box A18., Folder 2.1.3)
          - Peking, 1983 May - June (Box A18., Folder 2.1.3.1)
          - Interview with Oliver Tambo, Tanama? (Box A18., Folder 2.1.3.2)
            - (Tape 2), (Also included: Extract of speech made at AKFM Rally), 1985
          - Press Conference, Addis Ababa, 1988 May 28 (Box A18., Folder 2.1.3.3)
          - Brief Statement and Questions: Press Conference, Moscow, 1989 March (Box A18., Folder 2.1.3.4)
        - Recorded Questions for possible response by President Tambo on the occasion of the OAU meeting, Addis Ababa, 1984 (Box A18., Folder 2.1.4)
        - Notes made by Oliver Tambo on Principles of Organisation (Box A18., Folder 2.1.5)
        - Back Exercises/Breathing and Relaxation Techniques (Box A18., Folder 2.1.6)
      - Other Individuals (Box A18., Folder 2.2)
        - Canon John Collins Memorial Service, St. Paul’s Cathedral, 1983 February 23 (Box A18., Folder 2.2.1)
        - Norma and David Kitson: Telephone conversations with various individuals including Oliver Tambo (Box A18., Folder 2.2.2)
        - Interview with Johnny Makhatini re negotiations/sanctions (Box A18., Folder 2.2.3)
        - Vigil/tribute to Johnny Makhatini (Box A18., Folder 2.2.4)
        - Operation Push Saturday Forum - Guest: Neo Mnumzana - ANC; Speaker: Donald Parsons. Rev. Jesse Jackson (2 cassettes: a - Part 1; b - Part 11), 1986 November 29 (Box A18., Folder 2.2.5)
        - Interview: Beyers Naudé; with V. Simpson. VOA, ( Voices of Africa), 1985 May 14 (Box A18., Folder 2.2.6)
        - Interview: Nkadimeng [Part 3], 1989 July 14 (Box A18., Folder 2.2.7)
        - Interview with King Sabata on the occasion of his 57th Birthday (2 cassettes), 1985 November 25 (Box A18., Folder 2.2.8)
        - Nthabi Simelane's account of the attempts of a white South African, Jeff to "recruit" her (Box A18., Folder 2.2.9)
    - Radio Broadcasts (11 items) (Box A18., Folder 3)
      - (News Items mainly recorded from Radio SA) (Box A18., Folder 3.1)
        Items include: Interviews with South Africa n politicians; Namibia n Elections; Sanctions; Imperialist Strategy; Gatsha Buthelezi’s New Year Message (Zulu); National Party Speeches.
      - My Country - Right or Wrong. BBC Production on the British Secret Service (2 cassettes) (Box A18., Folder 3.2)
      - South Africa - Evolution or Revolution. BBC Production (Box A18., Folder 3.3)
      - File on 4, 1986 May 6 (Box A18., Folder 3.4)
      - Music Collection and other miscellaneous items (51 items) (Box A18., Folder 3.5)
        Items include: Le Français sans peine - 2 cassettes; taking your own blood pressure; Amandla Ensemble; Freedom Songs; Msasani Lutheran Church Choir; Jazz ( Dollar Brand/ Charles Mingus, etc.); Soweto Teachers Choir; James Philip with Amsterdam Choir; MK Choir
  - Photograhs/Posters/Awards/Momentos and Other Miscellaneous Items (Box A19)
    - Posters (Box A19., Folder 1)
      - Welcome Home Comrade President (Box A19., Folder 1.1)
        Portrait of Oliver Tambo. Colours: Black, Green and Gold. Offset litho.
      - O.R. Tambo - We salute you (Box A19., Folder 1.2)
      - O.R. Tambo - Freedom Fighter, Commander, People’s Leader. (Box A19., Folder 1.3)
        3 photographs - Oliver Tambo addressing cadres. Colours: Black and Yellow. Offset litho. Issued by ANC Department of Information and Publicity, Johannesburg.
    - Photographs (Box A19., Folder 2)
    - Awards/Momentos and other miscellaneous items (Box A19., Folder 3)
      Items include: medallions (various); certificates (various); badges and other miscellaneous items such as a comb in shape of a plane (made out of scrap metal taken from American planes shot down over Vietnam).
- Series B: Office of the President, 1962-1992
  - ANC Correspondence addressed directly to/from Oliver Tambo (Box B1)
    - 1962-1969 (11 items) (Box B1., Folder 1)
      Subjects include attendance of a Conference in Addis Ababa, February 1962; threatened deportations from Botswana to South Africa.
    - 1971/1972 (10 items) (Box B1., Folder 2)
      Correspondents include Fred Dube. Subjects include NEC Meeting scheduled for June 1971; Report by Fred Dube on Black Americans/South Africans/Members of the ANC/Georges Paper/Scholarships; activities of Mxolisi.
    - 1973 (Box B1., Folder 3)
      Subjects include Khartoum Symposium on Afro-Arab Liberation Movements; Liberation Committee: ANC/ PAC Unity Question; M. G. Buthelezi.
    - 1977 (12 items) (Box B1., Folder 4)
      Correspondents include Maxwell M. Mlonyeni (Publicity Unit); Eric Singh. Subjects include discussions between the Publicity Unit and the Chama Cha Mapinduzi ( CCM) Youth Wing, University of Dar-es-Salaam Branch re ANC publicity; 3 300 medals of Chief Lutuli; request from ANC students in Cuba for literature.
    - 1982-1984 (5 items) (Box B1., Folder 6)
    - 1985 (5 items) (Box B1., Folder 7)
      Correspondents include Wolfie Kadesh; Luthuli Detachment Wankie Committee; Phylis Naidoo. Subjects include publication of Oliver Tambo's speeches; 13 August (1967), A Monumental Landmark - Wankie Campaign.
    - 1986 (26 items) (Box B1., Folder 8)
      Correspondents include Z. Pallo Jordan; Lindiwe Mabuza; Zarina Maharaj; Eric Singh. Subjects include invitation extended to Oliver Tambo to be the main speaker at the UN Institute for Namibia's 7th Graduation Ceremony; Towards the Reconstruction of South Africa by Albie Sachs; results of Z. Pallo Jordan's interview with Yugoslav Embassy; claims of "fraudulent" activities of a certain Moosajee; request for Oliver Tambo to use his influence to release two detainees: Augustine Bhekizazi and Rev. Patrick Simangaliso Mkhatshwa; application for marriage; invitation by the City Council of Sydney; poetry series focusing on the death of Olaf Palme; visit of the Swedish Foreign Minister/Rev. Jesse Jackson; conference of the Women's Section of the ANC: message; reaction to the decision taken at the Harare Summit/fate of Theresa Ramashamola; Statement on the Internecine Fighting at KTC.
    - 1987 (4 items) (Box B1., Folder 9)
      Subjects include Polisario’s victory; resignation of Godfrey Pule ( Godfrey Moshoeu) from the ANC/granted asylum in Sweden; Dakar meeting: an assessment.
    - 1988 (9 items) (Box B1., Folder 10)
      Correspondents include Nathaniel M. Masemola; Alfred Nzo. Subjects include premises for the Luthuli Services.
    - 1989 (19 items) (Box B1., Folder 11)
      Correspondents include ANC Students Union ( Bulgaria); Fred Dube; Solly Simelane; Jack Simons; Ann Marie Wolpe. Subjects include congratulations sent to Walter Sisulu in Polls Moor Prison on his 77th Birthday by Oliver Tambo and Alfred Nzo; relevant parts of De Klerk's statement on ANC.
    - 1990 (19 items) (Box B1., Folder 12)
      Correspondents include Kader Asmal; Abby Chikane (Chief Representative: Namibia); Wayne Fredericks; Frene Ginwala; H. Makgothi (Assistant Secretary General); Ngoako Ramatlhodi. Subjects include questions re need for the Political Research Unit/Political Committee (Office of the President); National Union of Mineworkers ( NUM) student delegates; SANSCO ( South African National Students Congress) Campaign re the renaming of the E. C. Mango College, Kangwane in honour of Oliver Tambo; death of Francis Meli; suggestions on the part of Frene Ginwala for two of Oliver Tambo's speeches: educational issues - South African university degrees (includes a statement to WUS/ UNESCO Seminar - Paris on Academic Freedom).
    - 1991 January - March (9 items) (Box B1., Folder 13)
      Correspondents include Lawson Naidoo. Correspondence with Nelson and Winnie Mandela. Subjects include message of support extended to Winnie Mandela; meeting (Jubilee Centre, London) to discuss a draft Constitution for a post-apartheid South Africa; message of condolences on the assassination of Bheki Mlangeni/ Bachana Matthews Mokoena and Alfred Mokoena/ Jabulani Nobleman Nxumalo; education crisis; division of South African artistic community; invitation extended to Oliver Tambo and/or Nelson Mandela to open ANC National Conference.
    - 1991 April - June, 1992 (17 items) (Box B1., Folder 14)
      Correspondents include Denis Goldberg; Titus Maleka (Umkhonto we Sizwe - PWV Region); Ngoako Ramatlhodi. Correspondence with Winnie Mandela. Subjects include concern on the part of family members re political prisoners - Antonio du Preez/ Derrick McBride/ Gordon Webster; Isithwalandwe Awards; Denis Goldberg's observations on problems faced by the ANC; impassioned appeal urging Oliver Tambo not to step down from his role as President in the forthcoming ANC elections; message of sympathy delivered on the conviction and sentence of Winnie Mandela; problems experienced by Umkhontho we Sizwe in the PWV Region; Statement: Appeal to Hunger Strikers from Comrade Nelson R. Mandela; holding of a meeting between the ANC and the Afrikaner Volksunie.
    - Undated Correspondence (12 items) (Box B1., Folder 15)
      Correspondents include: Kadar Asmal; Wolfie Kadesh; Albie Sachs.
    - Mail Book, 1987 February - 1989 May (Box B1., Folder 16)
      Lists of outgoing mail from the Presidents Office.
  - ANC - General (Box B2)
    - Correspondence (56 items), undated, 1971-1991 (Box B2., Folder 1)
      - Correspondents include Brutus, Dennis; Choabi, Seretse; Joseph, Helen; Kodesh, Wolfie; Mbeki, Govan; Mbeki, Thabo. (Box B2., Folder 1.1)
      - Mfenyana, S. (Administrative Secretary, 10 items), 1977 November - December, 1984 (Box B2., Folder 1.2)
      - Masondo, C. (Presidential Secretary, 15 items), 1986-1990 (Box B2., Folder 1.3)
      - Makgothi, H. G. (Presidential Secretary, 3 items), 1977 October - November (Box B2., Folder 1.4)
      - Mongalo, A. (Deputy Secretary for Presidential Affairs, 46 items), 1986-1990 (Box B2., Folder 1.5)
      - Correspondence re Visas (13 items), 1986-1990 (Box B2., Folder 1.6)
    - Memoranda, 1969-1992 (Box B2., Folder 2)
      Items include draft Memorandum on a proposed programme of non-violent and unifying resistance to apartheid after the Sabotage Act; Memorandum of the ANC to the UN Special Committee on Colonialism; Memorandum of the Delegation of the ANC to the Central Committee of the Rumanian Communist Party, Bucharest; Memorandum to the leadership of ANC from the Department of National Intelligence and Security (17 items).
    - Reports (Box B2., Folder 3)
      - 1967-1983 (Box B2., Folder 3.1)